<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<meeting meetingDateTime="2010-02-24T09:30:00-05:00" meetday="Wednesday" location="Room 804 LOB" id="meeting-Mental Health and Developmental Disabilities-6-2009" committeeName="Mental Health and Developmental Disabilities" committeeChair="Senator Thomas P. Morahan">
    <bills>
        <bill year="2009" id="S185A">
            <actClause>AN ACT to amend the insurance law, in relation to post traumatic stress disorder </actClause>
            <currentCommittee>MENTAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES</currentCommittee>
            <lawSection>Mental Hygiene Law</lawSection>
            <sameAs>A4572A</sameAs>
            <sponsor position="" fullname="MORAHAN">
                <id>MORAHAN-</id>
            </sponsor>
            <summary>
An act to amend the insurance law, in relation to post traumatic stress disorder

</summary>
            <title>Relates to report on the definition of &quot;biologically based mental illness&quot; and post traumatic stress disorder</title>
        </bill>
        <bill year="2009" id="S4058">
            <currentCommittee>MENTAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES</currentCommittee>
            <lawSection>Alcoholic Beverage Control Law</lawSection>
            <sameAs>A1801</sameAs>
            <sponsor position="" fullname="SCHNEIDERMAN">
                <id>SCHNEIDERMAN-</id>
            </sponsor>
            <summary>Changes community service to be compensatory service in certain sentencing alternative programs to distinguish such service from the service provided by volunteers. </summary>
            <title>Changes community service to be compensatory service in certain sentencing alternative programs</title>
        </bill>
        <bill year="2009" id="S6682">
            <actClause>AN ACT to amend part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date thereof </actClause>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="MORAHAN">
                <id>MORAHAN-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="DIAZ">
                <id>DIAZ-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="STEWART-COUSINS">
                <id>STEWART-COUSINS-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="VOLKER">
                <id>VOLKER-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <currentCommittee>MENTAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES</currentCommittee>
            <lawSection>Mental Hygiene</lawSection>
            <sponsor position="" fullname="HUNTLEY">
                <id>HUNTLEY-</id>
            </sponsor>
            <summary>Amends part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date. Amends part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date. Amends part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date. </summary>
            <title>Relates to subcommittees for mental health of community service boards; the effective date</title>
        </bill>
        <bill year="2009" id="S6683">
            <actClause>AN ACT to amend part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date thereof </actClause>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="MORAHAN">
                <id>MORAHAN-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="DIAZ">
                <id>DIAZ-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="MONTGOMERY">
                <id>MONTGOMERY-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="OPPENHEIMER">
                <id>OPPENHEIMER-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="STEWART-COUSINS">
                <id>STEWART-COUSINS-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="VOLKER">
                <id>VOLKER-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <currentCommittee>MENTAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES</currentCommittee>
            <lawSection>Mental Hygiene</lawSection>
            <sponsor position="" fullname="HUNTLEY">
                <id>HUNTLEY-</id>
            </sponsor>
            <summary>Amends part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date. Amends part R2 of chapter 62 of the laws of 2003, amending the mental hygiene law and the state finance law relating to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the membership of subcommittees for mental health of community service boards and the duties of such subcommittees and creating the community health and workforce reinvestment account, in relation to the effective date. </summary>
            <title>Relates to the community mental health support and workforce reinvestment program and the community health and workforce reinvestment account; effectiveness</title>
        </bill>
        <bill year="2009" id="S6772">
            <actClause>AN ACT to amend the mental hygiene law, in relation to the establishment of procedures or mechanisms to receive allegations of abuse or mistreatment of patients served by programs licensed or operated under the mental hygiene law and repealing certain provisions of such law relating thereto </actClause>
            <coSponsors position="" fullname="HUNTLEY">
                <id>HUNTLEY-</id>
            </coSponsors>
            <currentCommittee>MENTAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES</currentCommittee>
            <lawSection>Mental Hygiene Law</lawSection>
            <sameAs>A9825</sameAs>
            <sponsor position="" fullname="MORAHAN">
                <id>MORAHAN-</id>
            </sponsor>
            <summary>Requires the establishment of procedures or mechanisms to receive allegations of abuse or mistreatment of patients served by programs licensed or operated under the mental hygiene law; includes allegations received anonymously; requires toll-free number. </summary>
            <title>Requires the establishment of procedures or mechanisms to receive allegations of abuse or mistreatment of patients served by programs licensed or operated under the mental hygiene law; repealer</title>
        </bill>
    </bills>
    <notes>
The Committee will consider the following nominations:nnTodd L. Benham, as a Member of the Mental Health
Services CouncilnLuis R. Marcos, MD, as a Member of the Mental Health Services CouncilnJanice Laverne C
ooper, as a Member of the Mental Health Services CouncilnDavid R. Kaczynski, as a Member of the Mental He
alth Services CouncilnDavid H. Hamilton, as a Member of the Mental Health Services CouncilnJames H. Bopp
, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with
DisabilitiesnDale R. Angstadt, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Car
e and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnMary Hope Derby, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the
Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnJudith Eisman, as a Member of
the Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnLo
retta Goff, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Pe
rsons with DisabilitiesnAndrea Haenlin-Mott, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Commission non Q
uality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnRichard P. Johnson, as a Member of the Advisory
Council to the Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnJeffry Luria,
as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with D
isabilitiesnDeborah S. Lee, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Care an
d Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnLoretta H. Murray, as a Member of the Advisory Council to the Co
mmission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnRegis Obijiski, as a Member of t
he Advisory Council to the Commission non Quality of Care and Advocacy for Persons with DisabilitiesnNid
ia E. Martinez-Godfrey, as a Member of the nAdvisory Council on Alcoholism and Substance Abuse Servicesn
Judi F. Dolgow, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the Bronx nChildrens Psychiatric CenternAlvern
Gelder, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the BroomenDevelopmental Disabilities Services OfficenMa
rilyn D. Rodriguez, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the BrooklynnChildren's Psychiatric CenternP
atrick R. Rourk, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the St. Lawrence nPsychiatric CenternBeverly Pi
echowicz, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the Mohawk nValley Psychiatric CenternFrances Felice,
as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the nBinghamton Psychiatric CenternJoanna M. Papontos, as a Memb
er of the Board of Visitors of the nElmira Psychiatric CenternTadeusz S. Pietrzak, as a Member of the Bo
ard of Visitors of thenBuffalo Psychiatric CenternHilda R. Escher, as a Member of the Board of Visitors
of the nRochester Psy chiatric CenternJohn J. Wiktor, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the nBing
hamton Psychiatric CenternMarra Lori Schneider-Wendt, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of nthe Rockl
and Psychiatric CenternBarbara Bates, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the Rochester nPsychiatric
CenternGerry Trautz, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the nRockland Psychiatric CenternLuella R
ogers, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the nBroome Developmental Disabilities Services OfficenKa
thleen Ann Calvey, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the nBinghamton Psychiatric CenternJohn A. Mu
rphy, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the nRockland Psychiatric CenternElizabeth J. Pieper, as a
Member of the Board of Visitors of the nCapital District Developmental Disabilities Services OfficenPat
ricia C. Colbert, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the Hudson nRiver Psychiatric Centern.AR OFF;.
AR PUT;.PA;.AR HEADR ONnKatherine T. Less, as a Member of the Capital District DevelopmentalnDisabilitie
s Services OfficenWayne P. Rogers, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the Sunmount nDevelopmental D
isabilities Services OfficenLinda E. Sartoris, as a Member of the Board of Visitors of the CapitalnDistr
ict Developmental Disabilities Services Office
</notes>
</meeting>
